

SANJEEVANI HASABNIS

Sr. UI-UX Designer

Personal Details:

Full Name Sanjeevani Shriram Hasabnis

e-mail sanjeevanihasabnis@gmail.com

Contact +91 9960611836

Location **PUNE**

Brief about me

Creative engagement is my nature. So I keep myself busy into the things that gives outlet to my creative fluids. It could be any out of the box idea to solve design problem.

My career started as a designer and worked for more than eight years. Initially I worked into Graphic Designing where exposure to E-learning industry shaped me to understand an approach towards UID. In my current professional life as a UI and Visual Designer I had worked with many top clients serving many design solutions to craft web portals, web and mobile applications.

Creativity is the key element for any designer. Another important element that fascinates me that is a design principle, "Form follows function". Anything you add to a design has to serve a strong purpose that meets the goal of a user. And so my approach towards my design is to solve a problem. In recent time I groomed myself into front end development so that I could translate design concepts and ideas into reality using front end technology. I look forward to hone my skills and adopt new technologies that could make me a digital thinker and a strong problem solver.

Apart from my design skills, Indian Classical Music (Hindustani) is been part of my life since my childhood. I've learnt Vocal music as well as playing Tabla. This passion offered me plenty of grand opportunities to share the stage with many artists at reknowned music festivals.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION & CERTIFICATIONS

B.Com.

Passed in 1996 from Chintamanrao College of Commerce, Sangli.

Diploma in System Management

APTECH Computers, at Sangli.

Diploma in Graphic Designing for E-Learning

Certification under University of Pune and with collaboration of Maximize Learning (APTARA Corp.) Pune

Certifications

Completed certification course for UX Design by Interaction Design Foundation, Berlin

EXPERIENCE & SKILLS SUMMARY

- Worked as Sr. Visual Designer & UI Designer with Tech Mahindra
- Initiated for design solutioning at various projects.
- Strong ability in UI Design Reviews.
- Strong aesthetical sense of Visual Design

MY TECHNICAL SKILL MATRICS



TECHNICAL SKILLS & TOOLS

Technical Skills:

Usability Analysis, Wireframes, Prototype, Visual Design, User Interface Design, Design review, Customised Iconography, Style guide.

Tools:

Microsoft Office, Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Figma, Affinity Designer, Balsamiq, Axure RP8.

TECH MAHINDRA PROJECT EXPERIENCE

(Sr. UI-UX Designer)

1. Web Application

Project Description:

It is a platform that automates the collection, analysis, and testing processes of information on management systems. It then has the ability to enable a new, or upgrade the existing Network Elements configuration with the desired services with minimal or no manual intervention.

Role and Responsibility:

- Analyzed requirement and provided wireframe prototypes
- Developed design mockup with Landing page, dashboards with a sleek and innovative UI design.
- Worked on HTML CSS to make code repairs and optimize corporate applications.
- Designed unique Iconography
- Visual design skills with sensitivity to user-system interaction with the latest UI trends, techniques and technologies

TECH MAHINDRA PROJECT EXPERIENCE

(Sr. UI-UX Designer)

2. Web Application

Project Description:

It is a configuration-driven, end-to-end web application platform built by TechM as accelerator for our clients considering the low-code or rapid application development approach. It enables user to visually define their user experience on canvas allowing them to integrate/ configure data model, perform validations and interface with backend services with easy to use palettes.

Role and Responsibility:

- · Analyzed requirement and provided wireframe prototypes
- Strengthened company brand and identity by creating distinctive Logo.
- Developed landing pages, dashboards with a sleek and innovative UI design.
- Designed unique Iconography

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tech Mahindra, Location - Pune

November 2016 - April 2020

Role and Responsibility (Sr.Visual Designer & UI Designer)

- Analyzed requirements and designed, developed and implemented software applications.
- Developed landing pages, dashboards with a sleek and innovative UI design for multiple applications.
- Worked on HTML CSS to make code repairs and optimize corporate Applications.
- Designed unique Iconography
- Visual design skills with sensitivity to user-system interaction with the latest
 UI trends, techniques and technologies

Indecomm Global Services, Location - Pune

April 2015 - October 2016

Role and Responsibility (Graphic Designer)

- Worked on understanding requirements and designed exceptional E-learning Courses
- Developed various e learning assets, UI designs, conceptual icons, Info graphics and interactive animations for multiple projects
- Followed quality standards and procedures to minimize errors and maximize customer satisfaction.
- Collaborated with the team for organizational processes, achieve productivity standards and adhere to accuracy standards

WORK EXPERIENCE

Right Catalyst, Location - Pune

Right Catalyst, Location - Pune

Role and Responsibility (Graphic Designer)

- Working on Design Mockups for the clients in Articulate Storyline
- Flash to HTML5 conversion

Indecomm Global Services, Location - Pune

November 2011 - August 2013

Role and Responsibility (Graphic Designer)

- · Creating design briefs for approval
- · Presenting Design Mockups to the clients for feedback
- Reviewing the deliverables to deliver an error free and quality e-learning courseware
- Working on Client end (AVAYA) at Magarpatta city, Pune and using innovative design trends for interactive, engaging and pixel perfect Designs

Upside Learning, Location - Pune

February 2011 - August 2011

Indecomm Global Services, Location - Pune

July 2010 - February 2011

APTARA Corp, Location - Pune

February 2008 - August 2008

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Tabla Artist & Vocalist

- Accomplished Tabla Exponent and performed at many prestigious music festivals all over India.
- Interviewed at All India Radio and Television shows time to time.
- Approved artist of All India Radio for Vocal and Instrument- Tabla